Aslam Khan

Bulandshahr – UP West India Email: <u>aslam_sharif@outlook.com</u> Call @ +91-9897985237

Professional Synopsis

Supply Chain Professional 5 years of experience in a sensitive corporate environment. Outgoing and detail-oriented, I am proficient at Fleet, Distribution planning and Warehouse Operations. Also having Masters in Business Administration in Finance & Marketing.

Key Competencies

Warehouse OPS

Distribution Planning & Root Cause Analysis (RCA) Inventory Management Dispatches Order Processing

Transportation

Vehicle Tracking Control Fleet Managemet Export/Import Effectively manage 150+ drivers/fleets.

Software Skills

SAP ERP, WMS, ORACLE Office 365, MIS & BI Reports Order Processing & e waybills

Career Overview

Since Oct-2015Limited, -KSA **2013-2015**- India

Branch Supervisor, Bakhashab Transport & Trading Co.

Senior Officer, Usha International Limited, Indore

Employment History

Oct-2015 - Jun 2018 Branch Supervisor, Bakhashab Transport & Trading Co. Limited, Dammam- Saudi Arabia

Key Duties & Responsibilities: -

- Prepare the drivers' schedule to ensure delivery of shipment as per the consignment plan and report any delays along with the cause of delay to guarantee the optimization of manpower hours and cost efficiency.
- Follow up with production for pre distribution of plastic shipments to clients, if there is any deviation prepare Root Cause Analysis report to sort the problems.

- Effectively manage 150+ drivers/fleets and make approx. 600 trips inside KSA & GCC with client Sabic Petrokemya.
- Meet on time delivery (OTD) requirements and follow on discrepancies with suppliers and Customer Service.
- Trace vehicles through GPS Tracking Software & take driver follow-up for ensuring delivery on time.
- Stakeholder management; adequately and proactively inform Customer Service departments, Global Service Centers and suppliers.
- Guarantee the effective planning/scheduling of the movement of vehicle & goods through driver scheduling and routing while ensuring accurate record keeping of related matters (such as way bills, incidents, etc.) to meet operations requirements and business objectives.
- Contribute to the identification of opportunities for continuous improvement of systems, processes and practices considering 'international best practice', improvement of business processes, cost reduction and productivity improvement.
- Comply with all relevant safety, quality and environmental management policies, procedures and controls across the operations function to guarantee employee safety, security legislative compliance, delivery of high quality products/service and a responsible environmental attitude.
- MIS Reports: Daily Dispatch Report, Daily & Weekly OPS Report & Driver Income Statement.

Achievements; -

- o Manage 3 branches Riyadh, Dammam & Jeddah.
- $\circ\;$ Successfully logistics setup of 46 trucks with client Saudi Chemical in all three regions of KSA.
- Lead the team of 63 peoples including 3 coordinators & 60 drivers across KSA & GCC Countries.

2013-2015 Senior Officer, Usha International Limited, Indore - India

Key Duties & Responsibilities: -

- Performed many of the following tasks, raising quotations, handling customer requests, producing reports, growing the business and maintaining client records.
- Pioneer in setting up logistics and supply chain management operations, monitoring, and inspection of goods issued & Accounting of Stores of the company to ensure timely delivery of goods.
- Handling transporters- Negotiating, arranging of trucks etc. for dispatch. Transporter freight verification and approval from HO.
- Maintaining and assisting the preparation of reports, forms records, supporting documentation and other information needed in the support of delegated administrative responsibilities.
- Physical stock verification on monthly/quarterly and annual basis including spare parts inspection as per instructions with SCM -HO & Commercial Teams.

- To maintain cleanliness within the premises and send photographs weekly to HO-SCM.
- To ensure the proper maintenance of MHEs & Fire Extinguishers available in Plant.
- Sound knowledge of SAP MM- Order Processing, Material Movement (Inward & Outward), BI Reports, Invoicing Execution, Replacement & Cannibalization of Material through SAP Module.
- MIS & Record Keeping Managing record of Inbound and Outbound shipments & reporting same to clients.
 Preparation and submission of Defective Products Inspection Reports to Clients Weekly.

Education

Sr No.	Institution	Qualification	Grad e	Year
1	VIET - Greater Noida	MBA	1st	2013
2	IP College, Bulandshahr	B. Com	2nd	2011
3	Azad Public School, Bulandshahr	Senior Secondary	1st	2008
4	Azad Public School, Bulandshahr	High School	2nd	2006

Interests
Languages
Personal Information

Cricket, Travelling, Cooking & Enjoy Travelling Hindi (Mother), English (Fluently) & Arabic (Basic)

Indian National, born 10-Sep-1991, Married.